No!
"不！"
That's the only word we hear in the latest cute baby video to go viral.
这是最新走红的可爱宝宝视频中我们听到的唯一词汇。
But it's not the words that baby Orla says that has made this video so popular. It's the fact that her babbling clearly mimics the distinctive Scouse accent from Liverpool.
但让这个视频如此受欢迎的并不是宝宝奥拉说的词语，而是她的咿呀学语明显模仿了利物浦独特的"斯考斯"口音。
This now-famous infant may only have been born in 2022, but the different accents of babbling babies have been investigated for many years.
这位如今已成名的小婴儿可能只是在2022年出生的，但人们对咿呀学语婴儿的不同口音已经研究了多年。
A study from 2009 found that French babies tend to cry with a rising intonation, while German babies' cries often have a falling intonation.
2009年的一项研究发现，法国婴儿的哭声往往带有升调，而德国婴儿的哭声通常带有降调。
Other studies have shown American and French babies reflecting syllables from English and French respectively, and that babies with parents who speak a tonal language, like Mandarin, had a greater range of tones in their crying.
其他研究表明，美国和法国婴儿分别反映出英语和法语的音节，而父母说声调语言（如中国普通话）的婴儿，其哭声的音调范围更广。
So why does this happen?
那么为什么会这样呢？
As children develop, they practise making the sounds of the language that they hear around them.
随着孩子的成长，他们会练习发出周围听到语言的声音。
It's natural that they pick up the sounds and rhythms that surround them.
他们自然而然地学习周围的声音和节奏。
In fact, babies start to learn language from their mother from three months before birth.
事实上，婴儿从出生前三个月就开始向母亲学习语言。
However, it's not just the language of immediate family and caregivers that has an impact.
然而，产生影响的不仅仅是直系亲属和照顾者的语言。
Professor of developmental psychology, Caroline Floccia, highlights studies suggesting that children are more likely to acquire the accent of their environment than that of a parent who has an accent that is foreign to that location.
发展心理学教授卡罗琳·弗洛西亚强调，研究表明，孩子更可能习得所处环境的口音，而不是父母那种与当地不同的外国口音。
Why is this important to know?
了解这一点为什么重要？
Well, what it shows us is that babies are learning language through practice, and that the more time that parents spend interacting with their children, the greater the opportunity for this there is.
它向我们表明，婴儿是通过练习学习语言的，父母花越多时间与孩子互动，这种学习的机会就越多。
While babbling babies may not be able to say many words, studies estimate that they can understand many times the number of words than those that they can actually say.
虽然咿呀学语的婴儿可能说不了很多词，但研究估计，他们能理解的词汇量是他们能说出的词汇量的许多倍。
Giving babies exposure to a greater number of words, allows them to better build their vocabulary.
让婴儿接触更多的词汇，能使他们更好地建立词汇量。